Lagos, 101245 | +2347011733379

elemagodspower@gmail.com | https://elemagodspower.com/

I am a front-end developer experienced in Javascript, ReactJS, SASS, CSS, Semantic-UI, Bootstrap, HTML, Styled Components amongst other tools. I am also experienced in consuming APIs. I have additional backend skills such as creation of APIs with JWT authentication system using NodeJS and Express. And database skills with MongoDB and Firebase. I am also experienced in using Git and Github for team collaboration and version control. I build clean, appealing and functional websites which comply with the latest web standards.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Front-end Developer**

June 2019 - Present

Abia Tech Hub(ATH), Abia & Lagos

- Determines the structure and design of web pages.
- Stricks a balance between functional and aesthetic design.
- Ensures web design is responsive.
- Optimizes web pages for maximum speed, scalability and responsiveness.
- Develops user-oriented visuals and features using front-end languages
- Completes full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine SEO rankings.
- Consumes APIs to carry out operations in the projects.
- Uses git and github for collaboration with other developers

# $Front\text{-}end\ Developer\ Internship\ (Finalist\text{-}Winner)$

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

HNG, Lagos

- Worked with a team of developers, designers, marketers and product manager to ensure the timely delivery and launch of software products.
- Built authentication systems and consumed APIs for the implementation of various features in the projects.
- Built reusable code for future use
- Optimized web pages for maximum speed, scalability and responsiveness.
- Ensured that all software built had strong SEO rankings.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Web Development**

Jan 2019 - June 2019

ZTM Academy Bootcamp, Lagos

**Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) - Metallurgical and Materials Engineering** Apr 2014 - Apr 2019 *Federal University of Technology, Owerri* 

#### **SKILLS**

Javascript, ReactJS, HTML, CSS, SASS, Redux, Context API, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, JWT Authentication, Git and Github, Communication skills